**Is your home on the Teal Pumpkin Project Map?** - [Add it here](https://www.foodallergy.org/our-initiatives/awareness-campaigns/teal-pumpkin-project/map)

Close Alert Banner

* Food Allergy Essentials
    
* Information for you
    
* Join the Community

* Accelerating Innovation
    
* Elevating Research

* Advocacy
    
* Education Programs & Training
    
* Awareness Campaigns

Close Search

 [](https://www.foodallergy.org/)Search Toggle Mobile Nav Toggle

Join over 14,000 individuals and families managing food allergies who are sharing their food allergy stories and making a critical difference, helping to speed the search for new treatments and informing life-changing improvements in patient care.

You can help improve the lives of 85 million Americans impacted by food allergies and intolerances by supporting Food Allergy Research & Education (FARE) with your tax-deductible gift today.

    Food Allergy Essentials

    Information for you

    Join the Community

    Accelerating Innovation

    Elevating Research

    Advocacy

    Education Programs & Training

    Awareness Campaigns

Search Toggle

* Digital Policy

SHARE

SHARE

CLOSE

Digital Policy

Privacy Policy
==============

### Introduction

The mission of FARE (Food Allergy Research & Education) is to raise public awareness, to provide advocacy and education, and to advance research on behalf of all those affected by food allergies and anaphylaxis. The Food Allergy Research & Education website provides information, resources, referrals, and data intended to assist the public in managing life-threatening food allergies. The website also provides information for healthcare professionals and offers opportunities for volunteering in Food Allergy Research & Education fundraising events.

### Contact Information, Accessing, and Correcting Your Personal Information

If you have any questions about this Policy or you wish to review or correct your or your child’s personal information, you may contact us by U.S. mail, e-mail, or telephone at the addresses and numbers listed below.

Food Allergy Research & Education (FARE)  
7901 Jones Branch Drive, Suite 240  
McLean, VA 22102

email: contactfare@foodallergy.org

Telephone: 800-929-4040

### Our Commitment to Privacy

We at Food Allergy Research & Education recognize the importance of protecting your privacy. The purpose of this notice is to explain the practices and procedures we implement to protect your personal information, the way we use this information, and the choices you can make regarding our use of your personal information. This notice may be accessed by clicking on a “Privacy Policy” link that appears on each page of our website. Food Allergy Research & Education is committed to protecting your privacy and will honor this Policy.

### Changes to this Policy

Food Allergy Research & Education reserves the right to change this Policy at any time. To better serve you and your concerns about your privacy, we will notify you of any changes to this Policy by posting a notice prominently on the main page of our website ([http://www.foodallergy.org](https://www.foodallergy.org/)) indicating that there has been a change or update to the Privacy Policy. We encourage you to read this Policy.

### The Information We Collect and How We Use It

You may browse Food Allergy Research & Education websites without submitting personal information. However, if you choose to sign up for one of our e-mail lists; become a member; purchase products; or participate in an event, contest, or program, you will be asked for applicable personal data such as your name, gender, postal address, e-mail address, phone number, fax number, payment information, relationship to food allergies, and date of birth. The purpose of collecting such data is to assist FARE in contacting individuals and to collect payments made online. Food Allergy Research & Education also uses this personal information to advise users of new online materials, activities, and events, and to provide users with the opportunity to contribute to local and national programs and research initiatives.

Food Allergy Research & Education also collects personal information offline from volunteers, donors, and event participants. Such information may include name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, age, and information regarding the donation. The information is collected through offline registration forms, telemarketing appeals, and postal appeals. Food Allergy Research & Education uses this personal information to inform volunteers and donors of new materials, and activities and events that offer the opportunity to contribute to local and national programs and research initiatives.

### For EU-based visitors and subscribers, the following list provides information required by the GDPR relating to our use of your personal information.

* * *

**Personal Information**

Contact information, including name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number

**Legal Basis for Processing**

Consent to provide you with the content you request, as necessary for the performance of a contract.

* * *

**Personal Information**

Purchaser information, including credit card number, contact information, and billing information.

**Legal Basis for Processing**

Necessary to provide you with the content you request.

* * *

**Personal Information**

Demographic information, including age, preferences, gender, educational degrees, ethnic background, interests, and diabetes specific information.

**Legal Basis for Processing**

Legitimate purpose of providing tailored content to you.

* * *

**Personal Information**

Technical information, including your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses.

**Legal Basis for Processing**

Legitimate purpose of authenticating subscribers and optimizing website performance.

* * *

### Personal Health-Related Information

Personal information included in specific questions submitted to Food Allergy Research & Education is used solely as internal market research to help us better serve you. All other information entered on this site is used for aggregate demographic analysis only and no personally identifiable information is included in these analyses. Records are used to create aggregate reports for internal use only and are purged after one calendar year from the date of entry.  

### Payment Information

Payment information, such as credit card number and expiration date, is entered upon completion of  a sale or registration that requires a fee. Food Allergy Research & Education uses Global Payments and Verisign as third-party intermediaries to process your online donations and payments. Your credit card information is encrypted when submitted to the processor and transmitted over a secure connection between your computer and our server using Secure Socket Layers (SSL), the industry standard, to ensure protection of your private information. This sensitive personal information is not shared with third parties other than the processor and is stored by Food Allergy Research & Education for verification purposes or for recurring donations that you have authorized.

### Cookies, Gifs, Logs

Cookies are small text files that a website can place on a visitor’s computer hard drive to recognize repeat visitors, to facilitate a visitor’s use of the site and to track a visitor’s access to and use of the site.

Food Allergy Research & Education uses cookies to collect demographic data that help us better advertise our mission, programs, and events to potential visitors and to improve the functionality of the website and the experience for those who use our site. We receive data that includes the IP addresses, browser types, date/time stamp, donations, and sign-up information of visitors to our site.

In addition, Food Allergy Research & Education uses cookies to allow us to track which other websites have linked visitors to our site, what pages of our site are used by and are of interest to those visitors, and to link to information those visitors provide to Food Allergy Research & Education when they donate or sign up to take part in our programs and events.   
  
Cookies are used in the site in order to remember the user’s name. Sites containing other programs run by Food Allergy Research & Education may contain information as to how cookies are used on those sites.

### Sharing Your Information with Third Parties

Food Allergy Research & Education never shares or sells your e-mail addresses with or to third parties without your consent. Personal information collected from our donation pages is never shared with or sold to third parties. 

If you are a _California resident_, please [click](https://oag.ca.gov/privacy/ccpa) [here](https://oag.ca.gov/privacy/ccpa) to view “Your Privacy Rights” under California law.

### Public Forums

Food Allergy Research & Education advises users that personal information posted on the website is accessible only to members.

### Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act); we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products, and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

### Your Rights under the GDPR with regard to your Personal Data

Under the GDPR, EU-based visitors and subscribers have the rights to request from us access to Personal Data we store about you, to amend (or rectify) this data, to restrict our processing of the Personal Data, to erase the data, and to receive a copy of the data in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format (data portability). If you wish to invoke a right under the GDPR, you may contact us at contactfare@foodallergy.org. Please use the subject line “GDPR Request” in the subject line. Your e-mail should include a sufficiently detailed description of the GDPR right with which you seek assistance along with appropriate contact information. We may need to contact you for further information. FARE will notify you if your request has been granted or declined, or if exemptions apply.  
  
If you have provided consent for the processing and storing of your data, you have the right (in certain circumstances) to withdraw that consent at any time, which will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before your consent was withdrawn.  
  
You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) if you believe that we have not complied with the requirements of the GDPR with regard to your Personal Data.

### E-mail

**E-mail to Donors and Participants:** Donors to FARE and Participants of FARE events and programs may opt in for first- or third-party informational e-mails or opt out of all e-mail communication, except transactional emails, such as donation receipts and event/program specific information registered, you may email us at contactfare@foodallergy.org.

**E-mail to Users who have submitted a Request for Information:** Individuals who have requested specific information from FARE such as, but not limited to, e-newsletters are agreeing that FARE may contact them by e-mail in exchange for these free services. Users who fall under the CASL and GDPR regulations may opt in to or opt out of e-mails from FARE.

* Where permitted by law, users who do not wish to receive e-mail related to these activities or newsletters may cancel such services by following the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of any e-mail message from FARE at [contact@foodallergy.org](mailto:contact@foodallergy.org).
* Users who do not wish to receive e-mail may follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of any e-mail message FARE at contactfare@foodallergy.org.

The above are examples of opt-in/opt-out options and are not intended to describe every option on the FARE websites.

### Opting-Out of Future Food Allergy Research & Education Communications

You may opt out of Food Allergy Research & Education communications at any time by contacting [contactfare@foodallergy.org](mailto:contactfare@foodallergy.org).

Food Allergy Research & Education reserves the right to acknowledge your donation. If you have subscribed to any newsletter or publication published by Food Allergy Research & Education, you may unsubscribe by following the instructions in the e-mail to which you subscribed. You may also remove yourself from Food Allergy Research & Education e-mail list by contacting us via e-mail at: [contactfare@foodallergy.org](mailto:contactfare@foodallergy.org).

Please send us your name, phone number, and e-mail and postal addresses and which communications  you would like to opt-out of from Food Allergy Research & Education. Your e-mail address is never shared with third parties without your express consent.

### Our Commitment to Data Security

Food Allergy Research & Education implements physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to ensure that your personal information is protected at all times. Our servers are housed in an off-site, secured co-location facility. Employee access to personal information is strictly on a need-to-know basis. All employees are made aware of the Privacy Policy and of any updates or changes to it. Employees are reminded of the importance of protecting the privacy of our donors and Internet site users.

### Your Child's Privacy

We may collect your child’s personal information such as name, e-mail address, allergies, date of birth, gender, and postal address in order to register him or her in Food Allergy Research & Education activities such as school programs or contests.

Your child’s personal information is subject to all of the terms of this privacy policy. 

### Your Privacy Rights Under California Law

Websites owned by organizations that operate in California must comply with the privacy practices outlined in California privacy bill S.B.27 pertaining to the collection and use of personal information in direct marketing activities.

As discussed throughout this Policy, Food Allergy Research & Education honors your requests concerning your own personal information as it pertains to online and postal, and telemarketing communications as well as list rentals and exchanges.

If you prefer not to receive e-mail communications or postal mail or telephone calls from Food Allergy Research & Education, please notify us by emailing [contactfare@foodallergy.org](mailto:contactfare@foodallergy.org) or calling 800-929-4040. 

FARE Website Policies
---------------------

### [Terms of Use](https://www.foodallergy.org/terms-use)

The information provided on this site is designed to support, not replace, the relationship that exists between a patient/site visitor and his/her existing physician.

### [Linking Policy](https://www.foodallergy.org/linking-policy)

FARE encourages and permits text links to content on FARE’s website(s), provided that any such link uses the following guidelines when setting up a link to FARE’s websites.

### [Copyright Permissions Policy](https://www.foodallergy.org/media/2626/download)

FARE respects fair use and its role in allowing limited uses of copyrighted materials. FARE provides these Copyright Permission Guidelines to encourage and facilitate lawful use of FARE materials, which concern sensitive health topics and require expertise to create.

About FARE

FARE (Food Allergy Research & Education) is a 501(c)(3) charitable organization with the mission to improve the quality of life and health of those with food allergies through transformative research, education, and advocacy.

© 2024 FARE (Tax ID: 13-3905508) is a charitable organization as described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.

We use cookies to deliver the best possible experience on our website. To learn more, visit our [Privacy Policy](https://www.foodallergy.org/privacy-policy). By continuing to use this site, or closing this box, you consent to our use of cookies.

Close

FARE Resources
--------------

Please complete the following form to download the resource. You will be opted into FARE communications and can manage your preferences in the footer of any FARE email.

 First Name \*

 Last Name \*

 Email \*

What is 4 plus 5? 

State AL AK AZ AR CA CO CT DE DC FL GA HI ID IL IN IA KS KY LA ME MD MA MI MN MS MO MT NE NV NH NJ NM NY NC ND OH OK OR PA RI SC SD TN TX UT VT VA WA WV WI WY

 Zip

Top 9 Allergen Free Thanksgiving Cookbook
-----------------------------------------

Download these tasty allergy friendly Thanksgiving recipes for you and your family to make and enjoy! You will be opted into FARE communications and can manage your preferences in the footer of any FARE email.

 First Name \*

 Last Name \*

 Email \*

State AL AK AZ AR CA CO CT DE DC FL GA HI ID IL IN IA KS KY LA ME MD MA MI MN MS MO MT NE NV NH NJ NM NY NC ND OH OK OR PA RI SC SD TN TX UT VT VA WA WV WI WY

 Zip

Back to School Posters
----------------------

Please complete the following form to download the poster. You will be opted into FARE communications and can manage your preferences in the footer of any FARE email.

 First Name \*

 Last Name \*

 Email \*

State AL AK AZ AR CA CO CT DE DC FL GA HI ID IL IN IA KS KY LA ME MD MA MI MN MS MO MT NE NV NH NJ NM NY NC ND OH OK OR PA RI SC SD TN TX UT VT VA WA WV WI WY

 Zip

FARE Food Allergy Guide
-----------------------

Please complete the following form to download the FARE Food Allergy Guide. You will be opted into FARE communications and can manage your preferences in the footer of any FARE email.

 First Name \*

 Last Name \*

 Email \*

What is 4 plus 5? 

State AL AK AZ AR CA CO CT DE DC FL GA HI ID IL IN IA KS KY LA ME MD MA MI MN MS MO MT NE NV NH NJ NM NY NC ND OH OK OR PA RI SC SD TN TX UT VT VA WA WV WI WY

 Zip

Newark Workshop Videos Access
-----------------------------

Complete this form to view the recordings from the workshop. You will be opted into FARE communications and can manage your preferences in the footer of any FARE email.

 First Name \*

 Last Name \*

 Email \*

What is 4 plus 5 

State AL AK AZ AR CA CO CT DE DC FL GA HI ID IL IN IA KS KY LA ME MD MA MI MN MS MO MT NE NV NH NJ NM NY NC ND OH OK OR PA RI SC SD TN TX UT VT VA WA WV WI WY

 Zip

Holiday Recipe Book
-------------------

Download these tasty holiday recipes for you and your family to make and enjoy! You will be opted into FARE communications and can manage your preferences in the footer of any FARE email.

 First Name \*

 Last Name \*

 Email \*

State AL AK AZ AR CA CO CT DE DC FL GA HI ID IL IN IA KS KY LA ME MD MA MI MN MS MO MT NE NV NH NJ NM NY NC ND OH OK OR PA RI SC SD TN TX UT VT VA WA WV WI WY

 Zip
